<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking &amp; Security Fundamentals on Security Fundamentals</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/security-fundamentals/docs/funda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking &amp; Security Fundamentals on Security Fundamentals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/security-fundamentals/docs/funda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>nderstanding Network Architecture and Protocols: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/security-fundamentals/docs/funda/funda/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/security-fundamentals/docs/funda/funda/1/</guid>
      <description>## Introduction&#xD;Understanding network architecture and protocols is fundamental to anyone working in cybersecurity or networking. This tutorial provides a comprehensive overview of key concepts, including the OSI model, TCP/IP protocol suite, IP addressing, and common network protocols like HTTP and DNS. ## The OSI Model&#xD;The Open Systems Interconnection (OSI) model is a conceptual framework that standardizes the communication functions of a telecommunication or computing system without regard to its underlying internal structure and technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network Attacks and Defenses: Understanding and Mitigating Common Threats</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/security-fundamentals/docs/funda/funda/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/security-fundamentals/docs/funda/funda/3/</guid>
      <description>## Introduction&#xD;Understanding common network attacks is crucial for implementing effective defense strategies and protecting your network from malicious actors. This tutorial explores some prevalent network attack methods like Denial-of-Service (DoS/DDoS), Man-in-the-Middle (MitM), and ARP spoofing. We&#39;ll also discuss security hardening techniques to mitigate these threats and enhance your network&#39;s overall security posture.&#xD;## Denial-of-Service (DoS) and Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) Attacks&#xD;DoS and DDoS attacks aim to overwhelm a network, server, or online service with traffic, making it unavailable to legitimate users.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network Security Essentials: Protecting Your Network from Threats</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/security-fundamentals/docs/funda/funda/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/security-fundamentals/docs/funda/funda/2/</guid>
      <description>## Introduction&#xD;Network security is paramount in today&#39;s interconnected world, where cyber threats are constantly evolving. This tutorial explores essential tools and techniques to protect your network from various threats, including firewalls, intrusion detection and prevention systems (IDS/IPS), VPNs, wireless security, and network monitoring with Wireshark. ## Firewalls&#xD;Firewalls are the first line of defense in network security. They act as a barrier between your network and the outside world, filtering network traffic based on pre-defined rules.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
